Guide to the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees, Local 52 Records WAG.251
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees, Local 52 Records
1966-1998, 2009-ongoing
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees and Moving Picture Machine Operators of the United States and Canada. Local 52 (New York, N.Y.)
Margolin, Julius
WAG.251
1 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes.
3 websites in 3 archived websites.
International Alliance of Theatrical and Stage Employees, Local 52 was chartered in 1924 and represents technicians, artisans, and craftspeople in the entertainment industry in New York, New Jersey, Delaware, Pennsylvania, and Connecticut. The collection mostly contains meeting minutes generated by National Association of Broadcast Engineers and Technicians (NABET), Local 15 from 1966-1990, as well as photographs, directories, newsletters, and archived websites from Local 52.
Scope and Contents
International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees, Local 52 Records (1966-1990, 2009-ongoing) is mostly made up of Executive Board meeting minutes of National Association of Broadcast Engineers and Technicians (NABET), Local 15, a predecessor union of Local 52. Topics focused on during board meetings included membership materials; by-law changes; department classifications; elections; donations; and regional organizing. Other materials in the collection consist of newsletters; 50th anniversary program; budget meeting minutes; photographs from marches and strikes; and archived websites.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in repository; provenance is unknown. The accession number associated with this material is 1987.006.
An additional set of materials was donated by Julius Margolin at an unknown date. The accession number associated with this gift is 2018.057.
http://www.iatselocal52.org/index.html was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2009 as part of the Labor Unions and Organizations Web Archive. In 2014, this URL redirected to http://www.iatselocal52.org/. In November 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In Spring 2025, https://www.ialocal52.org/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2025.058.
Historical Note
International Alliance of Theatrical and Stage Employees, Local 52 was founded in the early 1920s and officially chartered by the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees (IATSE) in 1924. The local's jurisdiction includes New York, New Jersey, Delaware, Pennsylvania (with the exception of Pittsburgh), and Connecticut. The labor union represents technicians, artisans, and craftspeople in the entertainment industry including live theatre; motion picture and television production; and trade shows. After World War II, Local 52 competed with the Association of Documentary Technicians and Film Cameramen (ADTFC) and National Association of Broadcast Engineers and Technicians (NABET), Local 15 for members. In 1954, ADTFC membership was absorbed into Local 52. In 1990, NABET, Local 15's charter was dissolved and membership voted to become a part of Local 52.
Related Materials
The IATSE produced film, Assembly of New York State Federation of Labor Convention Parade, can be found in Series II of the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Moving Images Collection (FILMS 001).
National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians, Local 15 Records (WAG 076)
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged alphabetically by file title.
Theaters -- Employees -- Labor unions; Entertainment industry.; Motion picture industry -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States; Television broadcasting -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States; Margolin, Julius
- Apprenticeships, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Archived Websites, February 2009-ongoing
  Scope and Content Note
  Capture of Local 52's website began in 2009. The website included information on films and television series currently being filmed in the local's jurisdiction; a list of films shot in the United States; membership applications; links to other union websites; and other resources. In circa 2017, the website was redesigned and contained a history of the union; job descriptions; membership application information; and a non-discrimination statement. In 2024, the union created a new website at https://www.ialocal52.org/. The new website includes its history and organizing materials.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued semiannually.
- Business Agents/Managers, 1975-1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- By-Laws, 1975-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Candidates and Elections, 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Contracts, 1975-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Departments, 1975-1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Donations, 1975-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Dues, 1975-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1966-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9-16)
- Executive Board Meeting Motions, 1966-1989 (Box 1, Folder 17, Box 2, Folder 1)
- Executive Board Meeting Motions and By-Law Amendments, 1975-1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Finances, 1975-1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- General Membership Meetings, 1975-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Golden Jubilee Celebration, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- History of Local 52, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Local 52 News, 1973-1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Member Acceptances, 1975-1990 (Box 2, Folder 8-10)
- Member Policy, 1975-1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Membership Directory, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Minutes Approvals, 1975-1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Office Staff, 1977-1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Organizing, 1977-1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Pension and Welfare Fund/Annuity, 1975-1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Photographs, 1981-1998 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Regions, 1977-1990 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Testing, 1975-1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)